<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minorities in R on MiR Community</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Minorities in R on MiR Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>MiR Community 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Call for presenters for the MiR Fall Webinar Series!</title>
      <link>/blog/speaker_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/speaker_call/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Yan Krukov from Pexels
Be a presenter for the MiR 2022 Fall Webinar Series!   Are you interested in sharing your knowledge and your work to the MiR Community and beyond? We are looking for three speakers to kick off our MiR Fall 2022 Webinar Series! Topics include, but are not limited to: professional development(i.e. writing a resume, interview tips), sharing how to do a specific task using R (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR Community Highlight: Andy Murtha</title>
      <link>/blog/mir-community-highlight-andy-murtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mir-community-highlight-andy-murtha/</guid>
      <description>Mir Community Highlights offer a chance to meet MiR Community members and learn more about their professional journeys, experiences with R, and personal pursuits.
For this community highlight, please meet&amp;hellip;.
✨ Andy Murtha     What is your current role?     Tell us about yourself!     What are the most important skills in your current position? How did you develop these skills?     What are some difficulties you&amp;rsquo;ve faced in your career?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR Community Highlight: Yanina Noemí Bellini Saibene</title>
      <link>/blog/mir-community-highlight-yanina-noem%C3%AD-bellini-saibene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mir-community-highlight-yanina-noem%C3%AD-bellini-saibene/</guid>
      <description>Mir Community Highlights offer a chance to meet MiR Community members and learn more about their professional journeys, experiences with R, and personal pursuits.
For this community highlight, please meet&amp;hellip;.
✨ Yanina Noemí Bellini Saibene (she/her)     What is your current role?     I have a lot of hats but the job that pays the bills is as Research at National Institute of Agricultural Technology (INTA) coordinating the Agroecosystem Modeling Network and professor at Universidad Nacional Guillermo Brown (UNAB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Instructor Training Groups</title>
      <link>/blog/rstudio_instructor_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rstudio_instructor_training/</guid>
      <description>The RStudio Instructor Training Groups are active participant study sessions that allow individuals to work through the teaching and content portions of the certification exams. The RStudio Instructor Certification consist of three parts; 1) Participation in the RStudio Instructor training course on teaching methods 2) Complete a teaching 90-minute teaching exam that includes preparing and delivering a 15-minute demonstration lesson 3) Complete a 90-minute practical examination for the subject that the desire to be certified in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Survey results</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-01-11-climatesurveyresults/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-01-11-climatesurveyresults/</guid>
      <description>The Survey     The MiR community aims to support underrepresented R users of the World. In order to understand more about this community, a climate survey was conducted during the first half of 2021. Thanks to MiR volunteers&#39; translation, it was possible to answer to the questions in two languages: English or Spanish. From a total of around 190 community members, 74 of them responded the survey. In this post, we wrap up the results that came out from the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial Calendar</title>
      <link>/blog/editorial-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/editorial-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Blog Posts:     2021     Date: November 2, 2021 Title: &amp;ldquo;Congrats to Kerritt Saintal!&amp;rdquo;
Date: November 29, 2021 Title: &amp;ldquo;LGBTQ Rainbow Minority in Code&amp;rdquo;
 2022     Date: January 11, 2022 Title: &amp;ldquo;Website Update and Volunteer recruitment drive.
Talk about the updated website. This blogpost will be used for recruiting new volunteers for Social Media, Newsletter, Website, and Fundraising and rotating curator (Danielle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello 2022</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-01-11-hello-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-01-11-hello-2022/</guid>
      <description>To a new MiR year   Welcome to a new year! The MiR Community has so many plans for engagement and learning opportunities. This is the year for our global community to come together and share our knowledge skills and lift each other up.
The goals this year is to expand our community reach and engagement, from all levels of R knowledge and occupations. The MiR blog is the place we want you, yes YOU, to feel welcome and to engage with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website Design &#43; Call for Volunteers</title>
      <link>/blog/newwebsitevolunteerpositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/newwebsitevolunteerpositions/</guid>
      <description>Event Chair     MiR is a globally distributed organization. Events are at the core of what we do! The event chair’s primary responsibility will be to plan our calendar of events. In the next year, events (and the responsibilities thereof) may take several different forms:
virtual events: aligning our stream of speakers and content in-person/virtual conferences: connecting conference-goers from MiR for the premier annual R conference events (UseR, R Studio Conf) in-person meetups: organizing COVID-compliant local meetups (pandemic-pending)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rainbow Minority in Code</title>
      <link>/blog/lgbtqrainbowr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/lgbtqrainbowr/</guid>
      <description>LGBTQ Rainbow Minority in Code!     TL;DR I gave a presentation on Missing Narratives around Diversity and Inclusion in Research Software Engineering. My report on LGBTQ scientists who code (jobs that have “Developer&#39;&#39;, “Data”, “Software”, etc. in Twitter description) show that within the MiR Twitter followers with a pride flag account for 2.52%, and the followers of TheStemVillage Twitter account make up 2.05% (n= 486).
Any LGBTQ coders in the world ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congrats to Kerritt Saintal!</title>
      <link>/blog/rforusnov21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rforusnov21/</guid>
      <description>R for the Rest of Us Scholarship Winner Announced!     ![](kerrit_profile.png “image of Kerritt Saintal, winner of R for the Rest of Us Scholarship”))
In September, R for the Rest of Us, an organization that provides training and consulting in R, invited MiR members to apply to receive a full scholarship worth $899 to participate in the R in 3 Months program. With the R in 3 Months program, participants go through Getting Started with R, Fundamentals of R, Going Deeper with R, and lessons on using Git and GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrial &amp; Organization Psychology with R</title>
      <link>/past-events/iopsychwr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/past-events/iopsychwr/</guid>
      <description>Industrial &amp;amp; Organization Psychology with R     In this webinar, MiR Community member, Felix Wu will share how he and lab mates Evan Mulfinger, and Leo Alexander III use R as Industrial Organizational Psychologists. They will highlight an R Shiny app for adverse impact analysis and a study focusing on the impact of the Americans with Disabilities Act</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R is your R too</title>
      <link>/past-events/rstudioconf2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/past-events/rstudioconf2021/</guid>
      <description>My R is your R too     While the R community has made strides in increasing the representation and participation for women and users from underrepresented regions, there are still members of the R community that have expressed desires for a more inclusive space in addition to these strides. In addition, there are unique challenges that underrepresented R users experience in their respective workspaces or academic environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to know dplyr w/Daryn Ramsden</title>
      <link>/past-events/dplyer_daryn_ramsden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/past-events/dplyer_daryn_ramsden/</guid>
      <description>Getting to know dplyr with Daryn     In this webinar, RStudio certified instructor, Daryn Ramsden will go over the basics of wrangling data with dplyr! He will also highlight some of the new functions from recently updated dplyr 1.0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2 with Shelmith Kariuki</title>
      <link>/past-events/ggplotwshel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/past-events/ggplotwshel/</guid>
      <description>ggplot2 with Shelmith Kariuki     Do you want to learn ggplot2 or increase your confidence in ggplot2? In this webinar, Shelmith will go over the basics of ggplot2 to get you going!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Instructor Certification Panel</title>
      <link>/past-events/certpanel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/past-events/certpanel/</guid>
      <description>RStudio Instructor Certification Panel     Join RStudio Instructor Certification Panelists Greg Wilson, Yanina Bellini Saibene and Shelmith Kariuki for some fun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>MiR Community blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiR Community Sponsors</title>
      <link>/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sponsors/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
